Richmond, TX • 607.331.4902 • alexis.strong11@yahoo.com

SUMMARY

Motivated and highly inquisitive business professional with research, data and event coordination experience and expertise in mortgage loan processes. Astute problem-solver, meticulous with details, statistical analysis, and managing correlation. Dedicated to expanding subject knowledge and business competencies through continued research and training.

SKILLS

Data: Data Analytics, Advanced Microsoft (MS) Office

Research: Methodologies, Correlation Study on Child Academics

Event Coordinating: STEM Program, Project Management, Project Coordinator

Mortgage Lending: Loan Processing, Federal Regulations

EDUCATION

University of Houston-Downtown, Houston, TX Bachelor of Science in Psychology, Dec 2017

GPA: 4.0

Honors: Summa Cum Laude

Activities: Psi Chi - UHD, International Honor Society, National Society of Leadership

and Success

EXPERIENCE

STEM Program Coordinator, SUPERGirlsSHINE Foundation Houston, Texas Jun 2017 – Present

- Research and define roles for sponsors and donors prior to executing workshop modules that empower over 1,623 girls pursuing STEM professions
- Work directly with Foundation's President to plan workshop curriculum that successfully promotes and achieves a 100% high school graduation and Industry Internship Placement rate within 7 school districts and 4 universities
- Plan and execute structured STEM experiments and activities that encourage 87% of eighth graders to commit to high school STEM endorsed course plans
- Strategize with sponsors to create fundraisers and raise scholarship funds for the current 7 graduating seniors

Document Preparation Specialist, Polunsky, Beitel & Green, LLP Houston, Texas Oct 2020 – Sept 2022

- Researched, meticulously examined and constructed 500+ mortgage loan closing packages a month for a wide variety of private and commercial loan types
- Collaborated with over 85 corporate lenders and legal departments to evaluate applications and ensure adherence to all company policies
- Administered processing of all loan products, evaluated orders, and prepared required loan documents
- Managed documentation retrieval and follow-up by communicating extensively with title companies and corporate customers

Loan Review Specialist, Gregg & Valby, LLP Houston, Texas,

Jun 2018 - Oct 2020

Reviewed, analyzed, and prepared mortgage loan closing packages for each

loan type. Coached and onboarded 12 new employees and served as team lead to provide guidanceand support

- Documented processes daily and evaluated information to maintain accuracy and provide training to team members
- Identified gaps and attained missing information from commercial clients a
 Evaluated loan documents for accuracy to eliminate fraud and resolve all discrepancies